Mohammad Rafi Amin

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer passionate about crafting applications in Ruby, React, and JavaScript, boasting over 2 years of experience in developing solutions for projects of diverse scales. An ardent advocate of pair programming and emerging technologies, showcasing a knack for rapid and proficient adaptability and learning.

EXPERIENCE

Self-employed, Remote

Full-stack Developer, April 2022 - Present

- Built over 40 projects using different tech-stacks: HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, React/Redux, Ruby on Rails. Some of the projects are included.
- **StockList App**: A frontend web application that displays a catalog of financial values using Stock API. The app showcases a list of active stocks as well as daily gainers and losers. Built the whole application from the ground up. <u>Visit-site</u>:
- JustCold Web App: A full-stack app built using React as Frontend & Ruby on Rails as the Backend. The E-commerce app allows clients to see a list of Products and buy it. Visit-site:

TechnoHacks, India · Remote

Web Development Internship, August 2023 - Present

- Collaborated with a dynamic team to craft and implement web solutions, contributing to the successful launch of 5+ projects, resulting in a 20% increase in client satisfaction.
- Developed front-end interfaces for 5+ websites, optimizing user experience and reducing page load times by an average of 2 seconds. Visit-Site:

GAO RFID Inc, New York, United States · Remote Software Developer Internship, April 2023 - August 2023

- Spearheaded the creation and enhancement of content for company sub-industry websites, leading to a 30% boost in monthly page views and engagement.
- Utilized React and critical libraries to optimize front-end performance, resulting in a 40% decrease in website bounce rate <u>VisitSites</u>:

Moby Media Group, Kabul (Afghanistan) Network Administrator, July 2017 – March 2022

- Pioneered the setup and maintenance of network resources from the ground up, ensuring seamless connectivity for 500+ number of employees and departments.
- Implemented security protocols that reduced network vulnerabilities by 99.9%, safeguarding sensitive company data. <u>VisitSites</u>:

mrkamin2@gmail.com
Portfolio | Github |
LinkedIn | AngelList |
Medium | Twitter

SKILLS

Front-End:

JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Sass, Capybara, RSpec

Back-End:

Nodejs, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSql,

Tools & Methods:

Git, GitHub, Gitlab, Mobile/Responsive Development

Professional:

Remote,
Pair-Programming,
Teamwork, Mentoring,
Collaboration

PROJECTS

Doctor Appointment

This project is to make an appointment with a doctor. Doctor Reservation frontend is React frontend application for doctor book appointments. This application is responsive, and users can load, create, and delete doctors and reservations. Users need to sign up or sign in to access the application. They can sign up or sign in using the sign up and login forms.

- Built with: JavaScript | React | Ruby on Rails | Postgresql | HTML | CSS

Sunlight Electricity Services Company, Kabul (Afghanistan) IT Support Engineer, July 2012 – July 2017

- Modernized IT equipment and streamlined support processes, leading to a 80% increase in user satisfaction as measured by post-support surveys.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to troubleshoot and resolve an average of 8+ technical issues daily, contributing to a 99.9% decrease in overall operational downtime.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE, Sep 2022 - Present

Full-stack web Development, Computer Software Engineering

- Activities and societies: Student Mentor, 8 Hrs daily coding, Remote-pair-programming, Code-review.
- Spent 2000+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard Gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

Kabul University, September 2009 – July 2013 Bachelor Computer Science

VOLUNTEERING

MICROVERSE, Sep 2022 - Present, Student Mentor

- Mentoring junior web developers, and providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposing improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.

. View on Github

Food Recipe

The JavaScript capstone project is about building a web application based on an external API. The web app will have 2 or 3 user interfaces. the user can see the list of foods and is able to put comments and likes to each food.

- Built with: JavaScript | Webpack | HTML | CSS . View on Github

Space Travelers Hub

This is a React WebApp with real live data from the SpaceX API. The application will allow users to book rockets and join selected space missions.

- Built with: JavaScript | React | HTML | CSS . View on Github

To-Do list

A todo list is a practical tool for organizing tasks. It allows users to input, prioritize, and track activities, enhancing productivity and goal management in various aspects of life.

- **Built with:** JavaScript | Webpack | HTML | CSS
- . View on Github